Justin Rounds

Front-End Developer

justin.c.rounds@gmail.com

Summary

Software engineer, team leader, game developer, and 2d/3d artist with extensive web development experience for mobile and desktop. Passionate about UX. Loves JavaScript.

Specializing in web design & development, 2d/3d art & animation, game design, sound design. Works in Flash, Photoshop, Illustrator, After Effects, Maya, Blender, Actionscript 3, Unity, C#, HTML/CSS/Javascript, Ruby/Rails, Node.js.

Experience

Lead UI Engineer at Localytics

August 2015 - January 2016 (6 months)

Worked with product design and engineering teams to facilitate front-end development. Audited HTML, SCSS, and page load performance. Worked on strategies to reduce page weight and improve performance. Created revised style guide with UX design team. Helped establish component-based front-end architecture using React and Webpack. Collaborated with design and engineering to devise processes to rapidly iterate on the UI of a large-scale web application.

Head of Front-End Development at SessionM

March 2014 - July 2015 (1 year 5 months)

Coordinate with Product Design to manage projects and assign resources. Guide front-end development team and help inform decisions regarding completion of deliverables. Determine ways to improve existing processes and infrastructure. Work closely with developers to create a healthy and happy work environment. Help solve complicated infrastructure problems and contribute to software design decisions.

Front-End Engineering Team Leader at SessionM

June 2013 - February 2014 (9 months)

Managed front-end development team. Worked with Product Design team to establish deliverables and milestones. Worked on core infrastructure updates in Rails and JavaScript.

Software Engineer at SessionM

June 2011 - May 2013 (2 years)

Front-End Development for iOS and Android devices, Rails development, HTML5 Game development (specifically for mobile).

Flash Consultant at Viximo Inc.

February 2011 - May 2011 (4 months)

Worked with the Viximo team to create a poker game for integration with social networks, providing frontend Flash development services for the game client.

Senior Software Developer

June 2010 - November 2010 (6 months)

Developed social media games using Actionscript 3, HTML/CSS/Javascript, and Ruby/Rails.

President

March 2008 - June 2010 (2 years 4 months)

Jawbreaker Interactive provided art, animation, design, and development services for websites, video games, and virtual environments. I oversaw all business activities, managed the projects, and directed all creative.

Consultant at Linden Lab

October 2009 - February 2010 (5 months)

Worked with UI/UX design & Development team on version 2 of the Second Life Viewer, including implementing changes to the UI configuration files, creating graphic assets, and consulting on usability.

Software Developer

August 2007 - October 2009 (2 years 3 months)

Developed Flash applications for LiquidPixel's dynamic imaging server. Handled technical support of servers, software, and services. Managed imaging services projects.

3d Artist at Sun Microsystems

September 2007 - July 2008 (11 months)

Acted as 3d Technical Artist for the project's real-time 3d virtual collaboration environment. Built assets and worked with design team on 2d/3d interface solutions. Designed and developed a browser-based web application for editing virtual worlds.

Web Designer

August 2007 - July 2008 (1 year)

Combined 2d & Samp; 3d graphics/animation in a Flash site design reflecting 822 Digital's passion for video games. Designed, built, and integrated a Flash game component into the site with a database-driven high score board (PHP/MySQL).

Maya Instructor at Boston University Center for Digital Imaging Arts (CDIA)

August 2007 - August 2007 (1 month)

Taught basics of Maya and advanced skills required to create a simple character animation.

3d Artist

May 2007 - July 2007 (3 months)

Modeled, textured, and animated various low-poly assets for " The Wonderful End of The World"...

Graphic Design & Digital Media Specialist

June 2004 - June 2006 (2 years 1 month)

Designed websites, logos, and graphics for various DLDC projects, including redesigning templates for the University's libraries and the main DLDC website. Also developed web apps for accessing certain digital archives, and assisting library staff with web development.

Education

Center for Digital Imaging Arts at Boston University

Certificate in 3D Animation, 3d modeling, texturing, and animation, 2006 - 2007

School of the Art Institute of Chicago

Bachelor of Fine Art, Art & Technology, Sound, 1999 - 2003